Guide to the Bill Dixon Papers MSS.481
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Music, 1936, 1941, 1959-2012; 125.72 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 39 flat boxes, 17 tall LP boxes, 24 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize flat boxes, 1 rolled storage box, and 2 flat-file folders.; 402.54 Gigabytes in 1,214 digital files.
  - Subseries I.B: Performance Recordings, 1960-2011; 75 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 25 flat boxes, 16 LP boxes, 1 manuscript box, and 1 cassette box
    - Bill Dixon at Bimhaus, Amsterdam, July, 1979; cuid37129 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1680)
    - Bill Dixon -- "New Song", November 15, 1979; cuid37130 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_100)
    - "The Painter of Sound," Kevin Campbell, November 20, 1979; cuid37131 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_728)
    - Bill Dixon Ensemble -- Short Series, December 7, 1979; cuid37132 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_173, Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2068)
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Widoff Duets, circa 1985-1995; cuid37134 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_459, 481_476, 481_486, 481_488)
    - Laurie Moses, 1980-1983; cuid37138 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_721)
    - Jazz, Bill Dixon Orchestra, 1980; cuid37139
      - Audio (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_412)
      - Papers (Box 213, Folder 6)
    - Bill Dixon in London, 1980; cuid37140 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_440)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet at Middlebury College: First Set, circa 1986; cuid37143 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2247, 481_2251, 481_2248, 481_2273)
      VHS tapes 481_2247, 481_2251, and 481_2248 are all duplicates of 481_2273.
    - Quartet at Bennington College, 1980s; cuid37145 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1076)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (Trumpet), M. Pavone and J. Voigt (Basses), and Laurence Cook (Drums)
      Duration: 101 minutes
    - Sketch / Firenze, "For Cecil Taylor", 1980; cuid37146 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1652)
    - Bill Dixon Trio Concert at Bennington College, circa 1980s; cuid37147 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1662)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Mario Pavone, and Laurence Cook
    - Bill Dixon, Laurence Cook, William Parker Concert, circa 1980-1995; cuid37148 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1688)
    - "Winter Cries / Juxtaposition" by Kevin Campbell, January - April, 1980; cuid37149 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_717)
    - Bill Dixon Sextet, Teatro Romano, Verona, June 6, 1980; cuid37150 (Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1454, Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1992, Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1517)
      This performance features Bill Dixon, Arthur Brooks, Steve Haynes, Steve Horenstein, Alan Silva, and Freddie Waits.
    - Bill Dixon Sextet, Can de la Scala Club, Verona, June 7, 1980; cuid37151
    - Bill Dixon Sextet in Florence, Italy, June 15, 1980; cuid37152 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1660)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Arthur Brooks, Steve Haynes, Steve Horenstein, Freddie Waits, and Alan Silva
    - Bill Dixon Sextet in Monselice, Italy, June 16, 1980; cuid37153 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1678)
    - Bill Dixon in the 1980s, circa 1980s; cuid37156
    - Bill Dixon Selections: Autumn Festival, 1980-1992; cuid37157
    - Bill Dixon Trio at the Chapelle Des Lombards, Paris, France, June 18-24, 1980; cuid8739
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet and piano), Oliver Johnson (drums), and Kent Carter (bass)
      - Audio -- 1 of 3 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1545)
      - Audio -- 2 of 3 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1642)
        Duration: 90 minutes
      - Audio -- 3 of 3 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1719)
    - Bill Dixon Trio at the Chapelle Des Lombards, Paris, France, June 18-24, 1980; cuid8740 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1708)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet and piano), Oliver Johnson (drums), and Kent Carter (bass).
    - Imagine the Sound, circa 1981; cuid37040
      - Video -- 1 of 3 (Box 77, Betamax 481_2355)
      - Video -- 2 of 3 (Box 77, Betamax 481_2358)
      - Video -- 3 of 3, cuid37040C (Box 78, Vhs 481_2403)
        Duration: 50 minutes
    - Zurich, 1981; cuid37161 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1646)
    - Compilation Tape -- Performances at Bennington College, N.E. Repertory Theatre, and Verona, Italy, 1981; cuid37162 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1683)
    - Bill Dixon, March 25, 1981; cuid37163 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_789, Box 30, Audiocassette 481_869)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet -- First of Two Nights in Milan, Italy, April 11, 1981; cuid37164 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1740)
    - "Summerdance" Performance by Judith Dunn and Bill Dixon, May 16, 1981; cuid37165
      - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 76, Betacam 481_2354)
      - Video -- 2 of 2 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2267)
    - New England Repertory Theatre, Worchester, Massachusetts, June 15, 1981; cuid37166 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1654)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet), Mario Pavone (bass), and Laurence Cook (percussion)
      Duration: 62 minutes
    - Unlabeled Tape -- Likely an Italy Performance, November, 1981; cuid37167 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1573)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet Performance, November 5, 1981; cuid37168 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1656)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Mario Pavone, Laurence Cook, and Barre Phillips
    - Bill Dixon Ensemble at Teatre San Pedro, Padova, Italy, November 10, 1981; cuid37169 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1648)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet), Alan Silva (bass), Mario Pavone (bass), and Laurence Cook (drums)
    - Bill Dixon at Centro Jazz, Torino, Italy, November 11, 1981; cuid37170 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1685)
    - Bill Dixon Trio at the Salt Peanuts Club, Firenz, Italy, November 13, 1981; cuid37171 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1677)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet at Bennington -- Concert and Talk, December 5, 1981; cuid37172 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1686)
    - Bill Dixon Concert at Bennington College, December 5, 1981; cuid37173 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1743, Audiocassette 481_1750)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Laurence Cook, and Mario Pavone
    - Linda Dowdell, 1982; cuid37174 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_643)
      The cassette's label includes a tracklist.
    - Arthur Brooks, Paul Robeson House, May, 1982; cuid37175 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_642)
    - Solo Concert, Ferrari Gallery, Verona, Italy, June 26, 1982; cuid37176 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1663)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet in Concert, Bennington College (Informal, with Introduction Pertaining to Improvisation), September 30, 1982; cuid37177 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1668)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet), Mario Pavone and Joe Fonda (double bass), Laurence Cook (drums)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet in Concert, Paul Robeson House, Bennington College, December 3, 1982; cuid37178 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1636, Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1667)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet and flugelhorn), Mario Pavone and Joe Fonda (double bass), and Laurence Cook (drums)
    - Live NYC Music -- A Fest?, circa 1988; cuid37179 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_450)
    - Sisyphus Orchestral Work, circa 1988; cuid37180 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2508)
    - Dixon Trio Performance -- Vance R. Provey, Winter, 1983; cuid37181 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1643)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet "Cool Noire," Vienna, Austria, circa 1988; cuid37182 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1753)
    - Bill Dixon Concert Performance to Benefit Silo, May 8, 1983; cuid37183 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1729, Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1534)
      Duration: 160 minutes
    - East-West Travelling Dances, June, 1983; cuid37184 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_591)
    - "Economider," Bill Dixon, June 10, 1983; cuid37185 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_469)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet Performance at Bennington College, October 27, 1983; cuid37186
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Voigt, Pavone, and Laurence Cook
      - Audio (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1472, 481_1475, 481_1479, Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1730, 481_1738, 481_1739)
      - Video (Box 69, Vhs 481_1058)
    - Bill Dixon at World Music Hall, Wesleyan University, October 28, 1983; cuid37187 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1741)
      Duration: 92 minutes
    - "7 Improvs of the Same Piece in Chronological Order," With Interviews, November 21, 1983; cuid37188 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_458)
    - Bill Dixon and Chris Faris Duets, Bennington College, circa 1989; cuid37189 (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_505, 481_506, 481_508, 481_536, 481_537)
    - "Thoughts" Concert, Bennington College, Fall, 1984; cuid37198 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1659)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Mario Pavone, Laurence Cook, Kovall, and Eneidi
    - "Martin Luther King" Aircheck, January 16, 1984; cuid37199 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_499)
    - Piano Progression: Brooks, O'Neal, February 4, 1984; cuid37200 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_807)
    - Bill Dixon, Chris Faris, and Jeremy Harlos at Jennings, Bennington College, circa 1989; cuid37197 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_512, 481_538, Box 23, Audiocassette 481_514, 481_516)
    - Concert at Bennington College -- "Stations," "Maze," Solos, Ellington Songs, May 31, 1984; cuid37201 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1735)
    - Dixon Quartet Concert -- New Compositions, June 15, 1984; cuid37202 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1605)
    - Bill Dixon Ensemble, Paul Robeson House, Bennington College, October 4, 1984; cuid37203 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2560)
    - Concert at Bennington College, November, 1984; cuid37204 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1644)
    - Arthur Brooks and Dances at Paul Robeson House, November 8, 1984; cuid37205 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_704)
    - Fall Series, November 10, 1984; cuid37206 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1557)
      Featuring Mario Pavone, Laurence Cook, Eneidi, Bill Dixon, P.K.
      Duration: 74 minutes
    - Bill Dixon and Chris Faris Duets, circa 1990; cuid37207
      - Audio -- 1 of 19 (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_513)
      - Audio -- 2 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_565)
      - Audio -- 3 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_566)
      - Audio -- 4 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_571)
      - Audio -- 5 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_572)
      - Audio -- 6 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_574)
      - Audio -- 7 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_575)
      - Audio -- 8 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_576)
      - Audio -- 9 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_577)
      - Audio -- 10 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_578)
      - Audio -- 11 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_580)
      - Audio -- 12 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_581)
      - Audio -- 13 of 19 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_582)
      - Audio -- 14 of 19 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_607)
      - Audio -- 15 of 19 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_608)
      - Audio -- 16 of 19 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_609)
        Audiocassette 481_609 was identified as moldy in September, 2022 along with 10 other audiocassettes. These items are currently isolated from other items by housing them in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
      - Audio -- 17 of 19 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_610)
      - Audio -- 18 of 19 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_611)
      - Audio -- 19 of 19 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_612)
    - Ensemble, circa 1990; cuid37210 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_568)
    - Bill Dixon and John Blum, circa 1990; cuid37214 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_481)
    - Intima Danser 4-6 Dance Performance with Choreography by Marie Fahlin, circa 1990s; cuid37215 (Box 74, Vhs 481_2098)
    - Long Trumpet Solo -- Probably is Jerusalem, circa 1990; cuid37216 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2493)
    - Poss, Chris Faris, Leslie Winston, Bill Dixon, circa 1985-1995; cuid37217 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1672)
    - Concert Rehearsal, Middlebury College, Vermont, Fall, 1985; cuid37218 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1709)
      Featuring William Parker (double bass), Mario Pavone (double bass), Laurence Cook (drums), and Bill Dixon (trumpet and flugelhorn)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet Middlebury Concert, October 25, 1985; cuid37219 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1666, Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1733)
    - Bill Dixon, December 12, 1985; cuid37220 (Box 76, Betacam 481_2350)
    - Bill Dixon and P. Harrison Perform in Middlebury, Dixon Trumpet Solo at Wesleyan University, 1986; cuid37221
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Widoff Duets at Bennington College, circa 1986-1987; cuid37158
      - Audio (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_456, 481_457, 481_460, 481_463, 481_490, 481_692, Box 27, Audiocassette 481_691, 481_693, 481_694, 481_695, 481_696, 481_697, 481_705, 481_713, Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1687)
      - Electronic Records
    - Trumpet, 1986; cuid37222 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_054)
    - Dixon and Matt Henderson, Trumpet and Guitar, 1986; cuid37228 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_715)
    - Bill Dixon and J. Schenk Re: Music (Ensemble 1986), Trumpet -- Bill Dixon Practice I, cuid37229 (Box 29, Audiocassette 481_792)
    - Workshop: Middlebury [Illegible] Orchestra, 1986; cuid37230 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2531)
    - Compilation Tape - Bill Dixon Performs Original Works for Trumpet and Flugelhorn at Bennington College, circa 1986-1989; cuid37231 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1988)
    - Ensemble: Bindman on Dixon's Sabbatical, circa 1991; cuid37233 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1550)
    - Bill Dixon and Matt Henderson Duet, Spring, 1986; cuid37232 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_462, Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1511)
    - Arthur Brooks, circa 1991; cuid37234 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1615, 481_1617)
    - Concert, Boston, May, 1986; cuid37235 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2450)
    - Charlie's Tap Concert, Boston, Massachusetts, May, 1986; cuid37236 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1731, 481_1732)
    - Concert in Lexington, New York, September, 1986; cuid37237 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1681)
    - Third Stream Concert: Eric Zinman Trio, September 29, 1986; cuid37238 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_644)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet at Middlebury College, October 25, 1986; cuid37241
      - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2269)
      - Video -- 2 of 2 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2270)
    - Ensemble, October 30, 1986; cuid37243 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1628)
    - Solo Trumpet, November, 1986; cuid37245 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_084)
    - Bill Dixon Solo Piano, November 22, 1986; cuid37248 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1715)
    - Rossini - Wittman, Sage Symphony / Lattimore, Sage City, December 6-7, 1986; cuid37249 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2573)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet at Middlebury Concert with Penny Camprell Dance, December 25, 1986; cuid37250 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1055)
      Featuring Laurence Cook (Drums), Mario Pavone (double bass), William Parker (double bass), and Bill Dixon (trumpet and flugelhorn)
      Duration: 58 minutes
    - Bill Dixon and Leslie Winston, circa 1992; cuid37252 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_563)
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor, circa 1992; cuid37253 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_753)
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor CD #2, circa 1992; cuid37254 (Box 48, Dat 481_2694)
    - Bill Dixon and Cecil Taylor CD #1, circa 1992; cuid37255 (Box 48, Dat 481_2695)
    - IROP / "WORK", 1987-1991; cuid37256 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1983)
    - Sage City Symphony Rehearsal, October 11, 1987; cuid37260 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2547)
    - "Quinacridone: For Nelson and Winnie," Commissioned by the Sage City Symphony Orchestra, October 17, 1987; cuid37261 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2035)
    - "Quinacridone: For Nelson and Winnie," Commissioned by the Sage City Symphony Orchestra, November 17, 1987; cuid37262 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2499)
      Commissioned by Sage City Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Lou Calabro
      Duration: 75 minutes
    - Bill Dixon and Jared Van Dongen Performance at Bennington College, 1988; cuid37263
    - Vienna Rehearsal -- Dixon, Winston, Smart at the Paul Robeson House, Fall, 1988; cuid37264 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1639)
    - Bill Dixon in Verona, 1988; cuid37265 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1549)
    - Orchestra Work "Sisyphus," conducted by Bill Dixon, New York City, April, 1988; cuid37266 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2457)
    - Orchestra Rehearsal, New York City, April 1988; cuid37267 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2569)
    - Sisyphus Rehearsal at the Kraine Gallery, New York City, April 17, 1988; cuid37268 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2477, 481_2478, Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2567)
      Duration: 159 minutes
    - Sisyphus Performance at the Kraine Gallery, New York City, April 17, 1988; cuid37269 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2509, 481_2542)
    - Masada Echoes -- Bill Dixon, Ehran Elisha, Jeremy Harlos, May 17, 1988; cuid37270 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1077)
      Piece for trumpet, drums, and bass
      Duration: 19 minutes
    - The Murrays at Bennington College, May 28, 1988; cuid37271 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_560)
    - Bill Dixon Quartet, Knitting Factory, June 22, 1988; cuid37272 (Box 48, Dat 481_2708, Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1555)
    - Quartet at Teatro Romano, Verona, Italy, June 26, 1988; cuid37273
      - Audio (Box 14, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1105)
      - Video (Box 76, U-matic 481_2363)
        This video could not be digitized due to its condition.
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Oxley with Bailey, Brars, Waudsmann, Wand, Köln Stadtgarten, September 10, 1988; cuid37274 (Box 48, Dat 481_2689)
    - Piano Players (Murray), October 16, 1988; cuid37275 (Box 39, Audiocassette 481_1814)
    - Rehearsal of Large Ensemble Work, October 28, 1988; cuid37276 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_233)
    - Rehearsal -- Bill Dixon, Leslie Winston, Chris Faris, Spring, 1989; cuid37279 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_232)
    - Dixon Quartet "Cool Noir" Concert, Wiener Musik Galerie, Vienna, Austria, November 20, 1988; cuid37278 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1638, Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1675, 481_1679, Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2037)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet and piano), Leslie Winston (keyboards), Sidney Smart (drums), and Klaus Koch (bass)
    - Bill Dixon, Leslie Winston, Chris Farris, 1989; cuid37280 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_564)
    - Compilation including: Dixon / Faris or Harlos, Carriage Barn, 1989-1990; cuid37281 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_579)
    - Concert in Villeurbanne, France, circa 1994; cuid37282
      - Papers (Box 213, Folder 23)
      - Video -- 1 of 3 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2254)
      - Video -- 2 of 3 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2258)
      - Video -- 3 of 3 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2266)
    - Anniversary Overture, Sage City Symphony, April 15, 1989; cuid37283 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2548)
    - Bill Dixon and Jared Van Dongen Duets at Carriage Barn, Bennington College, June 21, 1989; cuid37284 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_749, 481_750, 481_751, 481_752)
    - Bill Dixon and Chris Faris Duets at Bennington College, 1989-1990; cuid37287 (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_507, 481_509, 481_510, 481_511, 481_515, 481_517, 481_519, Box 24, Audiocassette 481_567, Box 26, Audiocassette 481_613, 481_614, 481_615, 481_616, 481_617)
      Audiocassettes 481_613, 481_614, 481_615, and 481_616 were identified as moldy in September, 2022. These items are currently isolated from other items by housing them in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Duets -- Trumpet and Piano, Performed in the Carriage Barn at Bennington College, July, 1989; cuid37288 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2051)
    - Jerusalem Concert, circa 1990; cuid38989 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1072)
      Duration: 43 minutes
    - Bill Dixon and Jeremy Harlos Duets, 1990; cuid37293 (Box 23, Audiocassette 481_518, Box 24, Audiocassette 481_573)
    - Rotterdam, 1990; cuid37294 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_494)
    - Bill Dixon in Jerusalem -- Dress rehearsal and tour around the city, 1990; cuid37295 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2261)
    - Bill Dixon in Jerusalem -- Concert and Interview, 1990; cuid37297 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1067)
      Duration: 10 minutes
    - Bill Dixon in Jerusalem -- Rehearsal, 1990; cuid37298 (Box 69, Vhs 481_1071)
    - "Letters: Round Up the Usual Suspects", circa 1990; cuid37299 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2465)
      Duration: 47 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
    - "Letters: Round Up The Usual Suspects" Rehearsals, Fall, 1990; cuid37300 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2510)
      Duration: 126 minutes
    - "Letters: Round Up The Usual Suspects" Rehearsals, Fall, 1990; cuid37303 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2528)
      Duration: 32 minutes. Preservation note: Side 2 is blank.
    - "Letters: Round Up The Usual Suspects" Excerpts, 1990; cuid37301 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2514, 481_2536)
      Duration: 44 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
    - "Letters: Round Up The Usual Suspects" Excerpts, 1990; cuid37304 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2536)
      Duration: 91 minutes.
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Oxley, circa 1990-2005; cuid37302 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2516, 481_2521)
    - Compilation Tape -- Performances at Assorted Venues, 1990; cuid37305 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1956)
    - Bill Dixon and Tony Oxley -- Solo Piano, circa 1990-2005; cuid37306 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1665)
    - B. Cole and Bill Dixon Duet, Paul Robeson House, Bennington College, Fall, 1990; cuid37307 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1669)
    - Jerusalem, 1990; cuid37308 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1684)
    - Straud + 5 Poems Duet at Bennington College, 1990; cuid37309 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1689)
    - Bill Cole and Bill Dixon Duet at Paul Robeson House, Bennington College, Fall, 1990; cuid37310 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1696)
    - Jerusalem Solo, 1990; cuid37311 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1699)
    - Trio Performance in Jerusalem, 1990; cuid37312 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1703)
      Featuring Dixon, Horenstein, and an Israeli drummer whose name was not stated on the tape's label.
    - Agael by Hope Clark, "Webern Velvet" by Bill Dixon Performance at the Public Playhouse, Maryland, February, 1990; cuid37313 (Box 74, Vhs 481_2104)
    - Bill Barron Memorial Concert at Wesleyan University, February, 1990; cuid37314 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1710)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Ehran Elisha and Chris Faris
    - Bill Dixon Solo, Jerusalem Theatre, February 24, 1990; cuid37315 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1697)
    - Bill Dixon and Stephen Horenstein in Israel -- "Piece for Solo Trumpet and Flugelhorn," "Work for Ensemble", March, 1990; cuid37316 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2445)
    - 1990 Performances -- "Round Up the Usual Suspects" at Bennington College, Jerusalem Solos, March, 1990; cuid37317
    - Bill Dixon, Schlachthof [Illegible], Germany, March 14, 1990; cuid37318 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2506, Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2563)
    - Project Go -- First Concert and Gala Opening, Jerusalem Cinémathèque, March 20, 1990; cuid37319 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1695)
      Featuring the Jerusalem New Music Ensemble, Jeremy Montagu, Bill Dixon, and the Ethnic Contemporary Ensemble. Recording includes a trumpet solo by Dixon.
    - Project Go -- Ensemble and Duo Performances, Jerusalem Theatre, March 24, 1990; cuid37320 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1698)
    - Project Go -- Closing Concert, Tel Aviv Cinémathèque, March 25, 1990; cuid37321 (Box 37, Audiocassette 481_1700, 481_1702, 481_1704)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Stephen Horenstein, Jeffrey Kowalsky, and the Ethnic Contemporary Ensemble
    - Tape III, Abbey Lincoln Moseka and Bill Dixon/Jazz in a Museum Tape 2 Copy, April 27, 1990; cuid37323 (Box 31, Audiocassette 481_956)
    - Knitting Factory, May 20, 1990; cuid37325 (Box 38, Audiocassette 481_1726)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Matthew Shipp, W. P., Marc Edwards, and David Ware
    - John Blum's Concert, November 30, 1990; cuid37332 (Box 25, Audiocassette 481_480)
    - Bill Dixon, December 5, 1990; cuid37334 (Box 45, Audiocassette 481_2561)
    - "Letters: Round Up the Usual Suspects" Performed at Bennington College, July-December, 1990; cuid37331